So as the very final step on this part four of day two of week eight, we are now going to build an
8주 차 둘째 날의 4부 작업의 마지막 단계로 이 모든 걸 하나로 합칠 앙상블
ensemble model that brings all of this together.
모델을 만들 거예요
And first, I just wanted to show you that if I take a product like my microphone right here, the Quadcast
먼저 보여드릴 것은 여기 제 마이크 같은 것을 가지고 쿼드캐스트 하이퍼X 콘덴서
HyperX condenser mic, we've got these three objects now, Specialist Frontier and Random Forest, and
마이크를 가지고 세 가지 오브젝트가 있습니다 스페셜 프론티어 그리고 랜덤 포레스트입니다 각각에게
we can ask each of them to price this product.
제품의 가격을 물어볼 수 있죠
And you'll see we get these three numbers.
Get it, get it, get it! 숫자 3개가 보이죠
In this case, I think the frontier model is closest to the truth.
이 경우엔 개척지 모델이 진실에 가장 가까운 것 같아요
I seem to remember when we and maybe I must have had slightly different text when we called the specialist
제 기억으로는 지난번에 스페셜리스트 모델을 호출했을 때 텍스트가 약간 달랐던
model last time.
것 같아요
I think we got even better.
더 좋아진 것 같아요
We got like 129, I think, which is even closer.
129개 정도 있어요 더 가깝죠
Uh, but yes.
네, 맞아요
Anyways, you can see that the random forest didn't do so great, but the other two were, uh, were
어쨌든, 아무 숲이나 고른 건 별로였지만 다른 두 개는 괜찮았어요
So what we do right now is quite simple.
지금 하는 일은 간단해요
I take, uh, the first, I take a selected 250 test data points.
우선 250개의 데이터 포인트를 선별해서 봐요
Uh, I actually picked the ones from 1000 to 150 to keep it separate from the ones we've been using
1,000에서 150까지 중에서 골랐어요 실제 테스트에 쓰는 것과
for actually testing.
구별하려고요
Um, and basically I take each of those items, I find its description and I add in, what price do
기본적으로 각각의 물품에 대한 설명을 찾아서 추가합니다. 그리고 나서 전문가용 모델,
we get from the specialist model, from the frontier model, and from the random forest model?
프런티어 모델 임의의 숲 모델에서 얼마를 받을 수 있을까요?
And then I also have a list of prices where I put the actual true price of that item.
그리고 가격 목록도 있어요 해당 품목의 실제 가격을 입력하는 거죠 Put it's go
So we will end up with these four lists a list of specialist results from our proprietary LLM frontier
그래서 이 4개의 리스트가 GPT 4에서 나온 LLM 프런티어 래그 기반 결과와 추가 컨텍스트와
Rag based results that come from GPT four, with our extra context and the random forest results, and
임의 숲 결과 그리고 실제 수치를 포함한 LLM 프런티어 래그의 결과로 마무리되는데요
And so we build all of that.
그래서 그걸 다 만들었죠
I'm going to do a trick now which which is fairly common.
이제 트릭을 보여드릴게요 꽤 흔한 거죠
It's the kind of thing you can really play with.
갖고 놀 수 있는 물건이죠
I'm going to add two more, uh, into this.
여기에 두 개를 더 넣을 거예요
One of them is called mins and is the minimum of those three, and the other is called Max's and it's
하나는 최소라고 하는데 이 셋 중 최저이고 다른 건 맥스라고 하는데
the maximum of those three.
이 셋 중 최대죠
It's just it's another Um, fact that might might have some signal in there.
그냥 또 다른 사실인데 신호가 잡힐지도 몰라요
It might be useful to also look at what is the lowest estimate that the three models had, and what
세 가지 모델이 가장 낮게 추정하는 값과 한 제품의 가장 높은
is the highest estimate that they had for any one product.
값이 얼마인지 살펴보면 유용할 거예요
So now at this point we now have five results for each each of the 250 products, the specialist one,
현재 250개 제품마다 5개의 결과가 나왔어요 전문가용, 개척자용
the frontier one, the random forest one, the minimum of those three, and the maximum of those three.
무작위 숲용, 최소 3개 최대 3개 결과죠
They are sitting in five collections and I make a pandas dataframe out of those five specialist frontier,
현재 다섯 개의 컬렉션이 있는데 저는 개척지 숲과 민, 맥스를 바탕으로 판다스의 데이터
random forest, min and max.
프레임을 만들어요
And I take the prices, the ground truth, and I convert that into a series.
저는 가격과 그 기본 진실을 시리즈로 만들었어요
And I call this x and I call this y, which will be familiar to anyone from a traditional machine learning
이건 엑스 이건 Y라고 부를게요 전통적인 머신 러닝 배경의 사람들은 누구나 익숙할 이름이죠
And I can then do exactly what we also did during week six, which is I can say, uh, let's train a
6주 차에 했던 것과 똑같은 걸 할 수 있어요 선형 회귀 모델을
linear regression model, a simple linear regression that says what weighted average of these different
훈련해 보죠 간단한 선형 회귀로 시리즈별로 가정한 평균이
series gives you the best fit, the best result for this data.
데이터에 가장 잘 맞는다는 걸 의미해요
And so we do that.
그래서 그렇게 했죠
Um, and this is what we get.
Get it get it 그리고 이게 나왔어요
These are the coefficients.
이게 계수예요
So both the min's and the Max's get pretty high weighting.
gets in the Max 둘 다 상당히 무겁죠
Uh, so generally speaking it's taking its most, uh, been looking at some combination of the minimum
일반적으로 말하자면 가장 많이 고려하는 건 최저와
and the maximum as what it has latched onto.
최대치를 조합한 거예요
Um, then it's taken a healthy share of the specialist proprietary LM and a much smaller share of the
달 착륙선 전용 스페셜리스트 지분을 상당량 차지하고 프론티어 모델보다 훨씬 적은 지분을
frontier model.
차지하죠
And somewhat bizarrely, it's actually said the frontier.
좀 이상하지만 개척지라고도 하죠
There is there is some signal in Random Forest, but it's going to subtract out that, uh, you'll see
랜덤 포레스트에 신호가 있는데 그걸 빼면... 꽤 큰 신호가 가로채고
it's given a pretty large intercept and subtracted out a portion of the random forest numbers.
임의 숲 숫자의 일부를 빼는 게 보이죠
So that's a curious result, which indicates that maybe the random forest numbers weren't weren't that
흥미로운 결과예요 임의의 숲 숫자가 별로 좋지 않았다는 걸 의미하죠
good.
하지만 전체적인 퍼즐에 포함하는 게 유용할 것 같아요
Now you're probably you're going to thinking in your mind.
이제 머릿속으로 생각하실 거예요
You point out to me that random forest is already baked into these two, so I can't.
이미 아무 숲이나 넣었다고 하니까 못 하겠어요
You can't read too much into the fact that it's got a negative number there, because it's already factored
음수가 있다는 사실을 너무 많이 해석할 수는 없어요 최소와 최대 수에 이미
into the min and the max numbers.
포함되어 있으니까요
So you can run this again, taking out min and Max to probably get a better assessment of how it weighs
다시 실행해 보세요 min과 Max를 제거하면 세 모델의 무게를 더 잘
up those three models.
알 수 있을 거예요.
Um, so that that's all it takes to build an ensemble model, because now we can use this model to take
앙상블 모델은 이렇게 만들면 돼요 이제 이 모델을 이용해서 여러 요인을 취하고 가격을
in these different factors and predict a price, taking the best linear combination of the models that
예측할 수 있거든요 우리가 제공하는 모델의 최상의 선형 조합을 취해서요
So first I save that to ensemble model so that we've got that captured for the future.
그래서 우선 앙상블 모델에 저장해뒀어요 그걸 미래에 반영하려고요
We don't have to run it every time.
매번 할 필요는 없어요
And I have made a new agent called Ensemble Agent.
앙상블 에이전트라는 새 에이전트도 만들었죠
Let's go and take a look at Ensemble Agent right now.
앙상블 에이전트를 보러 가죠 지금 당장요
Here it is.
여기 있네요
This is the code for ensemble agent.
앙상블 에이전트 코드예요
And it's very simple.
아주 간단해요
Uh, it looks like I need to add some comments in here, which I will do.
여기에 주석을 달아야 할 것 같은데 달게요
So before you get to see this yourself, uh, it needs comments.
Get it get it.com/D렉터/D렉터/D렉터/D렉터/D렉터/D렉터/D렉터/D렉터/D렉터/D렉터/D렉터/D렉터/D렉터/D렉터/D렉터/D렉터/D렉터/D렉터/D렉터/D렉터/D렉터/DE 직접 보기 전에 의견을 말씀해 주세요
Bad meat.
상한 고기요
Uh, so sorry about that.
정말 죄송해요
In the init, we set it up by creating the three agents that it will be using for the different, uh,
init에서 설정하는 건 3가지 에이전트를 생성하는 거예요 가격 책정에서 각각
parts of its pricing.
사용할 요소들이죠
Uh, and we also load in its model weights the weighted combination when it comes to running the ensemble
어, 그리고 앙상블 에이전트가 가격을 불러올 때 그 제품의 모델 비율을
agent to do a price, uh, we calculate the price of the specialist by calling price.
추가해서 가격을 불러오는 것으로 전문가의 가격을 계산해요
We call price for the frontier.
개척지를 위한 가격이죠
We call price for the random forest.
임의의 숲을 위한 가격이에요
We build a data frame for X, including the min and the max.
X를 위한 데이터 프레임을 만들죠 최소와 최대를 포함해서요
And finally we call Model.predict to predict why that should really be Y hat if we're using data science
마지막으로 Model을 호출해요 왜 그게 돼야 하는지 예측하기 위한 예측을 데이터 사이언스
speak and we return that the prediction.
스피크를 사용한다면요 그걸 예측으로 반환하는 거죠
Uh, so it's hopefully crystal clear for you.
명확하게 이해하셨길 바라요
It's simply a way of packaging up the call to our linear regression model that gives a linear combination
선형 회귀 모델에 호출을 포장하는 방법일 뿐이에요 전에 만든 다양한
of the different models that we've built before.
모델의 선형 조합을 제공하는 거죠
And so with that of course, the next thing that you can imagine I tried out pricing the same, uh,
이제 다음으로 할 일은 같은 가격으로 가격을 매겨보는 건데요 여기 마이크를
the the the microphone I've got right here.
가져왔어요
And it came up with a number that's somewhere in the middle, which is exactly what we were expecting.
그런데 중간쯤 되는 액수가 나왔어요 우리가 예상했던 금액이었죠
I package it into a function ensemble processor, and then of course, I call the tester dot test with
함수 앙상블 프로세서에 패키지로 넣고 테스터 닷테스트를 앙상블이라고 불러요
Now, this takes a while to run because it's calling all these different models and modal takes a while.
실행에 시간이 좀 걸리죠 다양한 모델을 호출하고 모듈도 시간이 걸리니까요
So I've run it in advance.
미리 실행해뒀어요
And if you're watching this, remember it will take a few minutes for the first one while modal warms
이걸 보고 계신다면 첫 번째 모듈은 워밍업하는 데 몇 분
up, and then it's a few seconds for each of these.
걸리고 각각 몇 초씩 걸린다는 걸 기억하세요
Out they come and as you will see, there's a few reds in there.
여기 보시면 붉은 연어도 몇 마리 있어요
I will tell you.
말해 줄게요
Somewhat disappointingly, I was really hoping this would move the needle and beat, uh, the, the,
실망스럽습니다 이걸로 뭔가 바뀌길 바랐거든요 기존의 특허
the amazing proprietary model that we've got, somewhat disappointingly, using this, uh, approach
모델을 깨부수길 바랐는데 여러 모델을 조합하는 방식을
of Ensembling multiple models seems to have moved us a hair poorer, a hair worse for this test data
쓰다 보니 테스트 데이터 세트가 전보다 조금 더 약화되고 악화된
set, uh, than than we were at before.
것 같아요
But you've got to imagine that that's that's more an artifact to the fact that it's fairly noisy.
하지만 생각해 보세요 사실 꽤 시끄러운 소리에 더 가까운 인공물이에요
It's very, very close.
아주 근접했어요
It has to be an improvement that we're carrying out this ensemble of different models.
다양한 모델을 조합해서 작업하는 건 더 나은 결과가 나와야 해요
Um, but there's clearly some more work that needs to be done here.
하지만 아직 손볼 곳이 많아요
Uh, the chart looks looks very nice, but there's some intercept problem there that might be that that
해도는 좋아 보이지만 가로막기 문제가 있어요 가로막기 숫자가
intercept number was too high.
너무 높았던 것 같아요
Uh, on on what it did.
뭘 했는지에 대해서요
Uh, and rather than spending a lot of time iterating over this, I think this is the time to say it's
이 문제를 반복하는 데 많은 시간을 쓰기보다는 이제 당신에게 넘기겠다고 말할 때인
over to you.
것 같아요
Now, I've spent a fair amount of time on this, but not so much on the ensembling technique and on
이 동작에 시간을 많이 들였지만 조합 기술이나 다른 동작에는 별로 투자하지
some of these others.
않았어요
And it's wonderful to experiment with this because it's so easy to add on more terms, more serieses,
이런 실험을 하는 건 멋진 일이에요 더 많은 시리즈들을 추가할 수 있고 앙상블을 만들면서
and pass that into the linear regression as you build the ensemble.
선형 회귀 단계로 넘어가기 쉽거든요
And this is a data scientist's dream.
데이터 과학자의 꿈이죠
You've got data.
데이터가 있잖아요
You've got a clear, measurable, a clear way of determining success.
성공을 결정하는 명확하고, 측정 가능한 명확한 방법이 있어요
And lots to experiment on, lots of hyperparameters and quite quick gratification.
하이퍼파라미터도 많고 실험할 것도 많아요
You can make the change and see the response very quickly.
변화를 주면 반응이 아주 빨라요
So you can do better than me.
나보다 잘할 수 있어요
This is very much a challenge.
정말 어려운 과제예요
You're now armed with lots of good tools.
이제 좋은 도구들을 많이 갖게 되셨어요
You may have already built a proprietary model that beats me.
날 이길 만한 독점 모델을 이미 구축했을지도 모르죠
And even if not, you can, I'm sure use this ensembling technique to get ahead.
안 되더라도 이 조합 기술로 get up 할 수 있겠죠
So with that, that concludes the lab work for this part before we return to the slides.
이것으로 슬라이드로 돌아가기 전에 이 부분의 랩 작업을 마치죠
The just to say remember that whilst this the key objective for this was not necessarily to get super
다시 한 번 말씀드리지만 이 강의의 핵심 목표는 제품 가격에 대해 깊이 파고드는 것이 아닙니다
deep on how you price products, it was to solidify your understanding of things like vector embeddings,
벡터 엠베딩 같은 것에 대한 이해를 확고히 하는 것입니다 다양한 모델을 래그화하여
rag the running different models and go from a stage of being fairly confident with this kind of material
이런 물질에 대해 꽤나 자신 있는 단계에서 더 발전하고 매우 자신 있는 단계로 가는 것이죠
And I hope you've got there now.
여러분도 그렇게 됐길 바라요
And if you haven't, go back through these notebooks and go through each cell by cell and inspect the
경험이 없다면 이 공책을 다시 훑어보며 세포 하나하나를 살펴보고 아주
outcomes and convince yourself until you are very, very confident.
확신할 수 있을 때까지 결과를 점검하고 자신을 설득하세요
And I will see you back in the slides in the next video.
다음 비디오에서 슬라이드에서 다시 만나요